

☐ (+1) 814-777-7019 | **I** feng@gatech.edu | **A** fxiao.me | **D** xiaofen9 | **D** f-xiao

Summary_

First-year PhD. student at Georgia Tech. 6+ years experience specializing in the security tool development and OS hacking. Obtainted 14 CVEs from widely used software. Interested in developing proactive and adversarial approaches to protect computer systems.

Project Experience

Nodejs Program Analysis and Automatic Bug Finding

Atlanta, USA Oct. 2019 - Now

GEORGIA TECH

- Discovered Hidden Parameter Attack, a new type of attack in Nodejs ecosystem.
- Built HiPar, an automatic Nodeis bug finding framework by combining dynamic data flow tracking (Jalangi) and static syntax analysis (esprima).
- · Identified 5 previously unknown vulnerabilities from widely used nodejs modules (e.g., MongoDB, class-validator) and tested 60 of the most popular frameworks against them. We found that 39 of these frameworks suffers from at least one discovered vulnerability.

Test-driven Protocol Feature Identification and Debloating

Atlanta, USA

GEORGIA TECH

- Jul. 2019 Now
- Proposed an new method to identify and remove unwanted program logics from deployed protocol implementations.
- Built Deproto, a fully automatic protocol debloating framework combining dynamic tracing (Intel Pin) and static control flow analysis.
- Evaluated Deproto on several protocol implementations. The results indicated that Deproto is able to succuessfully remove features from complex protocols such as OpenSSL (588+ KloC).

Windows Kernel Hacking Wuhan, China

ANONYMOUS RED TEAM

Jul. 2017 - Feb. 2018

- · Proposed a new kernel object hijacking method which bypassed the latest Windows Kernel Protection (valid until Feb 2018).
- Developed an ALL-patform Windows rootkit (40+ KLoC C).

Security Assessment on Android App Cryptography

Shanghai, China

SHANGHAI JIAOTONG UNIVERSITY

Jun. 2016 - Aug. 2016

- · Discovered a new universal security risk shared by the majority of mobile apps, which can be exploited to forge apps' cryptographically consistent messages to abuse mobile services.
- Built a dynamic Android cryptography hook framework StupidHam to semi-automatically verified discovered bugs (https://github.com/ xiaofen9/StupidHam)
- · This new discovery honored as the most valuable vulnerability by Wooyun, the biggest bug hunting community in China.

Work Experience _____

Penn State University State College, USA

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Jun. 2018 - May. 2019

- · Proposed SVHunter, a security assessment and vulnerability finding tool for Software-defined networking (SDN) controllers. We open sourced SVHunter at https://github.com/xiaofen9/SVHunter.
- · Discovered 18 previously unknown security risks from 4 most widely used SDN controllers using SVHunter, and 9 CVEs were assigned for discovering these vulnerabilities.
- The proposed work has been accepted to IEEE S&P'20, the top 1 security venue.

Tencent. Co., Ltd. Shenzhen, China

SECURITY ENGINEER INTERN

Aug. 2017 - Sep. 2017

· Captured and mitigate one Oday attack (CVE 2017-9805) against servers of our company; found 8 high risk vulnerabilities from the products of Tencent.

Honors & Awards

CONTEST AWARDS

Rank 1st in XMCTF. 2017 Xiamen, China 2017 First Prize of National Information Security Contest. Shanghai, China Rank 6th in 0CTF. 2015 Shanghai, China Rank 2nd in BCTF. 2014 Beijing, China

Honors

FENG XIAO · RÉSUMÉ MAY 11, 2020

2019	Chair Fellowship.	Atlanta, USA
2018	Rednor IST Fellowship.	State College, USA
2018	ACM CCS Student Travel Grant Award.	Toronto, Canada
2017	LeiJun Scholarship (Top 1 out of 310).	Wuhan, China
2016	National Scholarship (Awarded to top 0.2% students nationwide)	Wuhan, China
2015	Yuanyi Scholarship.	Wuhan, China

Publication

Unexpected Data Dependency Creation and Chaining: A New Attack to SDN.

S&P'20

FENG XIAO, JINQUAN ZHANG, JIANWEI HUANG, GUOFEI GU, DINGHAO WU, PENG LIU

- Proposed SVHunter, a fully automatic vulnerability detection tool for SDN controller.
- Discovered 18 previously unknown SDN vulnerabilities.

PatternListener: Cracking Android Pattern Lock Using Acoustic Signals.

CCS'18

Man Zhou, Qian Wang, Jingxiao Yang, Qi Li, Feng Xiao, Zhibo Wang, Xiaofeng Chen.

• Discovered a new side-channel which is able to leak user inputs on Android platform.

Hacking the Brain: Customize Evil Protocol to Pwn an SDN Controller.

DEFCON'18

FENG XIAO, JIANWEI HUANG, PENG LIU.

• Discovered a previously unknown OpenFlow protocol design insecurity.

Enabling Secure Location Authentication in Drone (poster).

MobiCom'17

FENG XIAO, MAN ZHOU, YOUCHENG LIYE, JINGXIAO YANG, QIAN WANG.

• Proposed WiDrone, a multi-channel location cross-check system to mitigate GPS spoofing attacks targeted at CPS.

Education

Georgia Institute of Technology

Atlanta, USA

Ph.D. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

July. 2019 - Now

· Working on system security with Prof. Wenke Lee.

Wuhan University

Wuhan, China

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Sept. 2014 - Jun. 2018

• GPA: 3.87/4

Programming languages

Natively fluent: Python, C, Java, PHP

Conversationally fluent: JavaScript, C++, Matlab

May 11, 2020 Feng Xiao ⋅ Résumé 2